Zafran Akhmadery Arif

Pullman, WA 99163 • zafranarif@gmail.com • +1 509 338 5999 • bit.ly/LinkedInZafran

Professional Summary

A young leader who has demonstrated his skills and leadership by working in several non-profit organizations. A passionate individual who has a passion in Digital Literacy and has a specialization in Mathematical Modeling and Optimization. Have been invited to speak in various seminars and webinars, talked about education and digital literacy.

Education

Washington State University (WSU) Bachelor of Science, Applied Mathematics

Pullman, WA December 2022

Working Experience

Washington State University

Dairy Microbiology Lab Assistant

Pullman, WA May 2022 - Present

- Worked closely with the Professor, PhD Students, and Masters Students of Food Science and Human Nutrition Department in WSU.
- Assisted them with their research in microbiology for dairy products.

Bank Negara Indonesia New York (BNI NY)

Information Technology (IT) Intern

New York City, NY May 2021 - Jun 2021

- Trusted to work with the IT team in creating a design for the company's customer portal.
- Learned from other departments about how the businesses work.
- Assessed the strengths and weaknesses of the company's workflow.

Washington State University

Teaching Assistant & Tutor

Pullman, WA

Aug 2019 - Aug 2020

- Assisted the professors with **grading quizzes**, **homework**, and **exams**.
- Tutored students in **Business Calculus** and **Trigonometry** classes.
- Taught students mathematical concepts.
- Supported students by **identifying and solving** mathematical problems.
- Taught students in such areas as Calculus, Algebra, and Trigonometry.

Generali Indonesia

Jakarta, Indonesia May 2018 - Jul 2018

Actuarial Intern

 Worked closely with the Pricing Team and trusted to improve the quality of company's product using Excel and Visual Basic.

- Assessed data by utilizing Microsoft Office Excel.
- Helped the Actuaries in determining the price of an insurance policy based on multiple variables.

Skills and Interests

- Leadership
- Management
- Public Speaking
- Teamwork

- MATLAB
- F
- MySQL
- Python

- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft PowerPoint
- Microsoft Word
- Google Sheets

Zafran Akhmadery Arif

Pullman, WA 99163 • zafranarif@gmail.com • +1 509 338 5999 • bit.ly/LinkedInZafran

Leadership Experience

 PPI Dunia (Overseas Indonesian Students' Association Alliance) Secretary-General Director of Overseas Education and Culture Head of Education Information 	Main Office Aug 2022 – Sept 2023 Aug 2021 – Aug 2021 Aug 2020 – Jul 2021
 PERMIAS (Indonesian Students' Association in the USA) President of Pullman Chapter Vice Director of Organizational Development Head of Pullman Delegates (National Congress 2018 in Boulder, CO) 	USA Chapter May 2018 – Aug 2019 Sept 2018 – Sept 2019 Sept 2018
 IAAS (International Association of Students in Agricultural and Related Sciences) Board of Project and Sciences Head of Indonesian Delegates (61st World Congress in Croatia) 	Indonesia Chapter August 2016 – Jan 2018 Jul 2018 – Aug 2018

Projects and Activities

The 42nd ASEAN Summit

Indonesian Youth Delegate

- **Selected** by the Indonesian Ministry of Foreign Affairs.
- **Formulated** a **policy recommendation** for ASEAN Member States.
- Discussed the future of ASEAN with the President of Indonesia and 10 other ASEAN Head of States.

Linear Programming and Optimization

Senior Project at Washington State University

- Assessing Business Efficiencies using Data-Envelopment Analysis.
- Planning a multi-period team assignment based on the staff members' productivity, creativity, and teamwork skills.

Community Service Program

Social Project by IPB University

- Aimed to **improve the quality** of the villagers life in Indramayu City and their businesses.
- Helped the locals in **solving their problems** in fisheries, education, and environmental fields.
- Analyzed the business efficiencies of the local products (mostly fish product derivatives).
- Taught in one of the elementary schools basic mathematics as an honorary teacher.

Youth Agricareture

Village Concept Project by IAAS Indonesia

- Coordinated 8 teams that were spread into 8 different cities in Indonesia.
- Supported the 2nd SDGs (Zero Hunger) by helping local businesses to thrive with their agricultural products and its derivatives.
- **Improved the quality** of their products (taste, packaging, distribution, etc.)

Labuan Bajo, Indonesia

2023

Pullman, WA 2022

Indonesia

2017

Indramayu, Indonesia

2019